christianlouboutin.com 2018-06-30

# Privacy Policy - Christian Louboutin Online Website

This Site is intended for the personal use of individuals who reside in the United States interested in learning about the Company or purchasing Company products. This Site is not intended to attract or be used by minors under the age of 18 without verifiable parental consent, and the Company will not knowingly collect personal information from such visitors.

1\. Intended Audience of this Site

This Site is intended for the personal use of individuals who reside in the United States interested in learning about the Company or purchasing Company products. This Site is not intended to attract or be used by minors under the age of 18 without verifiable parental consent, and the Company will not knowingly collect personal information from such visitors.

2\. Your Consent

By using this Site, you agree with and accept the terms of this Privacy Policy. Whenever you submit personal information to the Company through this Site or in some other fashion, you consent to the collection, disclosure, use and retention of that information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

3\. Collection of Information About You

The Company collects personal information from its customers and prospective customers primarily to assist in providing premium designer products for fashion conscious individuals by, among other things, processing your order(s), replying to your questions; providing our newsletter, blog and new product updates via e-mail; facilitating a transaction you chose to enter into with our third party partner(s), and incorporating your feedback into improvements to our Site.

Registering and logging into the Site using a social media account. You may be able to register and log into the Site using a social media account, including your Facebook account. When you use a social media account to log into the Site, you may be able to use certain social features on the Site. For Facebook login, Facebook will ask your permission to share certain information from your Facebook account with the Site. This may include your first name, last name, gender, birthday, language, country, email address, profile picture, list of friends, and other public data that is part of your Facebook account. This information is collected by Facebook and is provided to Christian Louboutin LLC under the terms of Facebook’s privacy policy. You can control the information that the Company receives from Facebook using the privacy settings in your Facebook account.

Placing an order. When you place an order for a product through the Site, you are required to provide contact, billing and credit card information in order to complete the transaction. Contact and billing information from the online order form (name, billing and shipping address, phone number, and e-mail address) is used to process orders and provide you with information about the Company. This information, including your e-mail address, also is used to contact you in the event we have questions regarding your order or we need to notify you about the status of your order. The credit card information we collect is used to bill you for products you purchase and, if you provide prior consent, this information also may be shared with a third party partner.

Subscribing to newsletters. When you sign up for our newsletter (Loubi Times), blog (Loubi Blog) or new products updates (New Collection), we use your name and the e-mail address you provide to send you the material to which you have subscribed. You may opt-out at any time to any subscription by following the unsubscribe instructions or sending an email to [eboutique.usa@us.christianlouboutin.com](mailto:eboutique.usa@us.christianlouboutin.com) with the word UNSUBSCRIBE followed by your email address in the subject of the e-mail message (example: UNSUBSCRIBE youremail@emailaddress.com).

Recommending a product to a friend. When you recommend a product to a friend through the Site, we gather your friend’s name and e-mail address. This information is used only once to e-mail your friend to advise him or her about the product you recommend.

Responding to an online survey. We occasionally conduct our own online surveys in the course of which we ask visitors for contact information (such as e-mail address) and demographic information (such as zip code, age, and/or income level). We use contact information from our surveys to send users information about the Company. You may opt-out of the survey and also opt-out of any future mailings at the time of the survey. The demographic information is used to learn more about the types of people who visit the Site. This information currently is not shared with any other parties. We reserve the right to share this information with other parties in the future in an aggregated format that would not disclose any personally identifiable information.

You should carefully limit the personal information you voluntarily provide to strictly that which is necessary for the Company to respond to your inquiry or provide a rewarding experience during use of the Site.

4\. Automatic Collection of Information

As you navigate this Site, certain limited information can and may be collected automatically from you without your active involvement, using methods known as cookies and navigational data collection. Some of the information (e.g., type of web browser) does not identify who you are. Other information, such as your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address or originating domain, may identify you indirectly, when supplemented with other commercially available sources of information.

When you visit this Site, we send to your computer one or more cookies, which are small text files containing a string of characters that store information about a visitor when he or she navigates from one Web page to another. The Site’s cookies hold users' unique session identifiers, allowing our server to return correct information back to the user during navigation of the Site. Such information includes the user's shopping cart items, or whether he or she is logged in when requesting to view or modify personal information, including e-mail address, which may have been stored in our database in the past. These cookies uniquely identify your computer to the Site, but do not facilitate the gathering of personal information. We use cookies to improve the quality of our service by storing user preferences and tracking user trends. Most web browsers are set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of this Site, including adding items to your shopping cart and checking out, will not function properly if your cookies are disabled.

The Company also uses tracking technologies to gather anonymous information about your browsing habits. Links in our e-mail communications to recipients are tracked via web beacons once you visit the Site. Web beacons appear on the Site as 1x1 transparent images that transmit information such as your operating system, browser, resolution, geographical location, products ordered, and order total. This information is used to help our webmasters and marketers understand the behavior of visitors to the Site and the effectiveness of online and e-mail messages. Your information is submitted anonymously, and no sensitive or personally identifiable information is transmitted.

Furthermore, our computer servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website. These server logs may include information such as the date and time of your access to the Site, the length of time of your visit, the portions of the Site accessed, the number of times you visit and purchase from the Site, the IP address assigned to your computer, the type of browser used by your computer, the domain from which your connection to the Site originates, and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your computer.

We assign you a unique internal identifier to help keep track of your future visits. We use this information to gather aggregate demographic information about our visitors, and we use it to personalize the information you see on the Site and the e-mails you receive from us (should you grant us permission to send e-mails to you). We keep this information for our internal use; we do not share it with others. This information is in no way tied to your personal information, including your e-mail address.

5\. Collection, Disclosure, Use and Retention of Personal Data

Except as otherwise stated at the point of collection, we may use your information for improving the content of the Site, customizing this Site to your preferences, communicating information to you and subsequently updating such information, internal marketing and research purposes, and as further specified in this Privacy Policy. We may combine such information with other passively or actively collected information unless we specify otherwise at the point of collection.

The Company may transfer your information, including personally identifiable information, to third parties, including contractors we use to support our business (e.g., marketing services, fulfillment services, technical support, delivery services, credit card companies, and financial institutions), in which case we will require such third parties to agree to treat your information in accordance with this Privacy Policy or as you may otherwise have previously consented. In the event that you choose to place an order with one of our third party partners, we will, in some cases, share certain information, including your e-mail address with the third party partner in order to facilitate your transaction. We always will ask for your consent prior to sharing your information with any of our third party partners. We do not share your personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes unless you have affirmatively agreed in advance to such a disclosure.

The Company also may transfer your information

  * (i) to our affiliated companies;
  * (ii) in connection with the sale, assignment or other transfer of the business function of the Company to which the information relates, in which case we will require any such buyer, assignee or transferee to agree to treat it in accordance with this Privacy Policy;
  * (iii) to protect the rights, property or safety of the Company, its employees or visitors to this Site; or
  * (iv) in compliance with subpoenas or other valid court orders, in response to inquiries and requests from regulatory authorities, in connection with the prevention or detection of fraud, or as otherwise permitted or required by law. In addition, we will make full use of all information acquired through this Site or otherwise that is not identifiable to you. 

6\. Choices for Disclosure and Use of Personal Information

You may choose to prevent the Company from disclosing or using your personal information under certain circumstances (“opt out”). You may opt out of any disclosure or use of your personal information for purposes that are incompatible with the purpose(s) for which it was originally collected or for which you subsequently gave authorization. Furthermore, even where your personal information is to be disclosed and used in accordance with the stated purposes in this Privacy Policy, you may elect to opt out of such disclosure to and use by a third party that is not acting as an agent of the Company. On the other hand, the Company may disclose your personal information to a third party acting as its agent where this third party agrees in writing to provide at least the same level of privacy protection as is required by this Policy.

7\. Access and Correction

Through your account at the Site, you may access your basic personal information in the possession of the Company and correct inaccuracies of that information in our records. For any other issues concerning the accuracy of your personal information, please contact us in the manner specified in the “How to Contact Us” section below. We ask individuals to identify themselves and the information requested to be accessed and amended before processing such requests, and we may decline to process requests in limited circumstances as permitted by applicable privacy legislation.

8\. Security

The Company takes reasonable measures to safeguard your personal information against unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use or modification, whether or not in electronic format. We use industry-standard technological precautions in an effort to protect your personal information as you transmit it electronically from your computer to this Site and, furthermore, to protect it from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. Furthermore, the Company requires that employees and third-party administrators/processors access your personal information only on a “need-to-know” basis.

You should keep in mind that no combination of security measures can ever provide guaranteed protection all the time. We caution you that e-mail may be particularly vulnerable to unauthorized interception, eavesdropping, modification and spoofing, and, therefore, you should take special care in deciding what information you send to us via e-mail. Moreover, where you use passwords, ID numbers or other special access features on this Site, it is your responsibility to safeguard them.

9\. Enforcement

Any questions, concerns or complaints regarding this Privacy Policy or the Company’s treatment of personal information may be communicated by contacting us through this Site, sending an e-mail message to us at [privacy.usa@us.christianlouboutin.com](mailto:privacy.usa@us.christianlouboutin.com) or by writing to us at Privacy Officer, Christian Louboutin LLC, 306 West 38th Street, 3rd Floor New York, NY 10018, U.S.A.

When we receive a formal written complaint, our Privacy Officer will contact the author within a reasonable period of time regarding his or her concerns and attempt to resolve these concerns directly with this individual. If a complainant believes that the Company has engaged in possible unfair or deceptive practices and legal or regulatory violations in connection with its privacy obligations, he or she may file a complaint with the Federal Trade Commission through its website [http://www.ftc.gov](http://www.ftc.gov/). We will cooperate with the U.S. Federal Trade Commission to resolve any complaint regarding the collection, disclosure, use and retention of personal information that cannot be resolved between the Company and the complainant.

10\. Links to Other Websites

This Site may contain links or references to third-party websites that are not affiliated with the Company. The inclusion of any link does not imply the Company’s endorsement of any other company, its websites, or its products and/or services. Any such linked websites have separate and independent privacy policies which we encourage you to read carefully. Please be aware that the Company has no control over linked third-party websites and, therefore, no responsibility or liability for the manner in which the organizations that operate such websites may collect, disclose, use or otherwise treat your personal information.

11\. Other Terms

Your use of this Site is subject to our Terms and Conditions of Use.

12\. How to Contact Us

To correct or update any personal information previously collected by us, please follow instructions at the original point of collection on this Site, send an e-mail message to us at [privacy.usa@us.christianlouboutin.com](mailto:privacy.usa@us.christianlouboutin.com) or write to us at Privacy Officer, Christian Louboutin LLC, 306 West 38th Street, 3rd Floor, New York, NY 10018, U.S.A.

PRIVACY RIGHTS FOR CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS

A California resident who has provided personal information to a business with whom he or she has established a business relationship (“California customer”) is entitled to request information about whether the business has disclosed personal information to any third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. As a general matter, if the business has made such a disclosure of personal information, upon receipt of a request by a California customer, the business is required to provide a list of all third parties to whom personal information was disclosed in the preceding calendar year, as well as a list of the categories of personal information that were disclosed.

However, under the law, a business is not required to provide such lists of information if the business adopts and discloses to the public, in its privacy policy, a policy of not disclosing customer’s personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes unless the customer first affirmatively agrees to the disclosure, as long as the business maintains and discloses this policy. Instead, the business may comply with the law by notifying the customer of his or her right to prevent disclosure of personal information and providing a cost free means to exercise that right.

As stated in our Privacy Policy, Christian Louboutin LLC (the “Company”) does not share information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes unless you have affirmatively agreed to such a disclosure. If you do request that the Company share your personal information with a third party for that third party’s marketing purposes, we will only share information in connection with that specific purpose. We do not share such information with any third party on a regular or continual basis. To prevent disclosure of your personal information for use in direct marketing by a third party, do not opt in to such use when you provide personally identifiable information on this website.

Please note that whenever you opt in to receive future communications from a third party, your information will be subject to the third party's privacy policy. If you later decide that you do not want that third party to use your information, you will need to contact the third party directly, as the Company has no control over how third parties use your information. You should always review the privacy policy of any party that collects your information to determine how that entity will handle your information.

California customers may request further information about our compliance with this law by e-mailing [privacy.california@us.christianlouboutin.com](mailto:privacy.california@us.christianlouboutin.com). Please note that the Company is only required to respond to one request per California customer each year, and we are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this e-mail address.

1\. Changes to This Privacy Policy

If this Privacy Policy changes, the revised policy will be posted on this Site. Please check back periodically and especially before you provide any personal information to the Company. This Privacy Policy was last updated on June 20th 2014.
